♪ In the not-too-distant
future ♪
♪ next sunday a.d. ♪
♪ There was
a guy named joel ♪
♪ not too different
from you or me ♪
♪ he worked
at gizmonic institute ♪
♪ just another face
in red jump suit ♪
♪ he did a good job
cleaning up the place ♪
♪ but his bosses
didn't like him ♪
♪ so they shot him
into space! ♪
♪ We'll send him
cheesy movies ♪
♪ the worst we can find ♪
♪ la! La! La! ♪
♪ He'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪ then we'll monitor
his mind ♪
♪ la! La! La! ♪
♪ Now keep in mind
joel can't control ♪
♪ when the movies
begin or end ♪
♪ la! La! La! ♪
♪ Because he used
those special parts ♪
♪ to make his robot friends ♪
♪ robot roll call ♪
♪ cambot ♪
♪ gypsy ♪
♪ tom servo ♪
♪ crow ♪
♪ if you're wondering
how he eats and breathes ♪
♪ and other science facts ♪
♪ la! La! La! ♪
♪ Then repeat to yourself
it's just a show ♪
♪ I should really just relax ♪
♪ for mystery science
theater ♪
♪ 3000 ♪
[Female voice] 30 seconds
to commercial sign.
Hi, everybody. Welcome
to the satellite of love.
My name's joel. I'm still
marooned out in space,
and if you just tuned in,
I guess so are you.
Uh, we're expecting a call
from the nasties
who shot us up here
any second now. All right?
Uh, by the way, if you're gonna
go during the commercial
and make a snack,
uh, while you're digging
in the refrigerator,
think of me.
Get something delicious
and nutritious,
because I'll be eating
vicariously through you, so...
Commercial sign in five,
four, three, two...
Commercial sign now.
Be right back, okay?
Put it through the hoop,
joel.
Yeah. Cool.
Oop. Try not to look
so happy, you guys.
Here come the mad scientists.
They're calling.
Come in, joel, my little
free-floating vacuum monkey.
Hey, sirs. What's up?
Well, not my hair.
It's limp and lifeless.
I don't know what to do.
Just get on with
the invention exchange.
Stop looking at me.
Yes, what have you
got for us, joel-arini?
Well, sirs, the things
that I've been working on
is this new way
of teleporting food.
In the future,
they're not gonna have
drive-through windows anymore.
They'll have drive-by windows.
You just drive your car by
and they teleport the food
right into your stomach
using something like this.
Okay, I put this on, look at
an ordinary cookie, and...
[Crunching]
Whoa.
Delicious. Mm-mm.
Now here we'll try it
with a glass of milk.
This is the big slurpee size.
Mm-mm-mm-mm-mm-mm-mm.
- [Gulping]
- Hey.
[Slurping, gulping
continues]
It went down.
Mm-mm.
Teleportation.
What do you think, sirs?
Oh, very nice, joeley cakes.
Uh, larry, make a note
to call james doohan.
Oh, here's
our new development--
an entirely new concept
in oral hygiene.
Yes, we've employed
some of hollywood's top stars
to help us with our
new mouth-to-mouth
celebrity toothpaste.
Feel the cleaning power
of the stars' internal juices
as they go to work
on plaque and tartar buildup
in your mouth.
Here's jack nicholson
from witches of eastwick.
Blagh.
Mr. Creosote from monty python's
the meaning of life.
"Somebody get a bucket.
I'm gonna throw up."
And linda blair with real
head-cranking action.
"Your mother
flosses in hell."
Aah!
Well, what do you think,
joel-arini?
Well, I think
four out of five dentists
are gonna recommend
psychotherapy for you two.
[Both]
Thank you.
Well, joel,
your film today
is called moon zero two.
IT'S A LATE '60s ROMP
through the then lunar-crazed
consciousness of america.
And believe me, it doesn't
stand up to the test of time.
Stew on the broth of this one,
lumpy boy.
Enjoy!
Oh, we got movie sign!
Ho!
♪ Moon zero two ♪
Hey, it's in color.
Yeah.
Really bad music already.
This is great.
Hey,
the cartoon has landed.
Is this
a pink panther movie?
No, uh, I think it's, uh,
like nasa simulation,
kind of like.
Why would they
use cartoons?
Well, so astronauts
could understand them.
Ah.
♪ It's time
to fly deep space... ♪
Hey, I didn't know the russians
had cartoons.
♪ Go far, go wild,
go lonely... ♪
♪ New worlds are there
for the taking ♪
Is this petula clark
singing?
Peculiar clark.
"Petuliar"?
Titles mrs. Reedy's
third grade.
Whoa.
Just, you guys,
I got the beat.
Hey, he's on
the other side.
He's where you were.
Circle the moon.
Exactly. Good.
Rock it, joel.
You look like goldie hawn
on laugh-in.
Except for the hair.
And the body.
Hey, it's '60's glasnost.
Hey, that's old glory
he just--
oh.
♪ On the moon
where I'm livin' ♪
♪ need some help
to make me grow ♪
What'd you think,
you guys?
We'll let you know.
♪ I could use
a kind of loving... ♪
Oh, look at that.
He's beating the titles
out of him.
['60s POP MUSIC CONTINUES]
♪ Moon zero two... ♪
You still have the teleporter
thing on, joel.
Yeah, I'm gonna do a thing
where I put this on
and eat popcorn that's in
the galley later.
♪ We'll love the world
we land on ♪
♪ and love is... ♪
Hey, great club.
No atmosphere.
Can't believe there's
a cover charge on the moon.
Oh.
They're riding the moon.
No atmosphere.
Is the whole movie
like this, you guys?
Boy, I hope not.
I don't think I can take
two hours of this song.
- They're trashed.
- Cartoon's cool, though.
Are those the blue meanies?
No, that'd be--
that'd be wrong, paul.
I've got a hole
in me pocket.
Hey, it's donald trump.
He's chasing
the good guys away.
Doesn't make sense.
It makes perfect sense.
Hey, look.
It's the film.
♪ Moon zero two ♪
♪ moon zero two ♪
Whoa.
Uh, houston, I just spotted
an animated cartoon
on the surface of the moon.
[Imitates static]
Come in.
Looks like they're shooting this
out of the back of a van.
It's a renegade
air-conditioning unit.
It's an orbiting
garden weasel.
And an orbiting space ferret.
[Laughs]
Space ferret. Get it?
He's going out
to a space gazebo.
It must be cold.
This thing is huge.
Huh?
Looks like a little
orbiting ice machine.
Houston,
our central air is here.
But they didn't send
the duct work, over.
Boy, I hope
it's under warranty.
That's a pretty big hole
in that thing.
He's got the nintendo
power glove there.
Oh, they put
the danger warning light
right on the middle
of his back.
Space is a gamble.
Darn those space coons.
They got into
the garbage again.
Honey, we're getting
those rubbermaid cans.
This isn't
gonna happen again.
I'm not going in for this.
Boy, it's really quiet
in space, isn't it?
Yeah.
Except for the distant
sound of trumpets.
Maynard ferguson's
out there somewhere.
So, was it the raccoons,
honey?
Sort of seems like
a waste of cargo space
to bring along a conga band.
Darn coons
in my ricken' frackin'
soomin' hoomin'...
Oh, he's got v.P.L.
In a bad way.
Why don't we ever
talk anymore?
Hey, were you messing
with my stereo?
The treble's
all thrown off here.
Silence.
Let's go back
and look at the moon.
Maybe they're showing
the feature now.
Moon zero two
calling moon control.
[Radio]
Moon zero two,
this is moon control.
Zero two to moon control.
Moon control to major tom.
Two minutes
from outer approach.
Request
landing instructions.
He's got
playtex living elbows.
Look at that.
...bear 157.
Decelerate at 1.8 g.
Zero two understand.
157 at 1.8 g. Over.
Snap it up, zero two.
This is pan am
moon express,
and we're just
ten minutes out.
That is your hard luck,
moon express.
First come, first down.
And you are
an hour behind schedule.
Hey, he flipped 'em off.
We're gonna have
to jettison your mustache,
you realize.
Here we go then.
Hey, look.
There is a man in the moon.
...announce the arrival
of flight--
there's a space
blue light special
on quadrant b-9.
If you're moon zero two,
I wish you'd sell
that thing along with
all the other space rubbish
you collect.
Don't say hi.
I don't think
I caught the name.
I'm the second officer
of the moon express.
You delayed us
for nearly two minutes.
If you took off on time,
you might land on time.
- I don't see that--
- I thought you were seeing
our passengers
through customs.
- I was just
telling this man--
- you can't
tell this man
anything about anything.
But feel free to tell him
something about nothing
or a little about a lot.
Uh, you'll have
to excuse my friend.
He's kind of a weenie.
Thank god
not all of them make it.
Dan, get this
over to the scrapyard.
Oh, with your permission.
And don't take
anything less than
12,000 moon dollars for it.
I'll try.
I've just got time
for a shower.
I wanna talk to you
a minute.
Come on then.
- My name is taplin--
- please.
Turn and face
the immigration identification
computer please, miss.
I'm here for
the gumby wedding.
Test your love.
Flaming! Great.
Is there a message for me?
The message desk's
over there, miss.
Thank you.
Good evening, mr. Hubbard.
Wow, it's castro.
I'm sorry, mr. Hubbard.
I hope you enjoyed
your trip, sir.
No more or less than a hundred
other trips I've taken.
Where's the armor all?
That's a nifty
little charmer.
J.j. Hubbard.
So that's 100% hubbard.
- Is he always like that?
- Sure, to the likes of us.
Sometimes he's 50%.
What does he want up here?
- Oh, I don't know--
- are you getting shorter, bill?
If it was mine,
he could have it.
Cheap.
Listen, I was...
Talking to personnel
back at earth base.
[All make wind sounds]
[Joel coughs]
--Back in
the corporation, bill.
They starting
exploration flights again?
- No.
- No, sorting boxes.
- But, uh--
- when they outfit
the first flight to mercury.
Tell them to call me.
Come on, bill.
You know the answer to that one.
We don't have your number.
It's not listed.
--To line the rocket tubes
for journeys like that.
We've got regular flights
to mars and venus.
- What more do you want?
- I'm not
coming back
into the corporation--
wow, did he get that shirt at
a molly hatchet concert?
--Not a mechanically-minded
wet nurse.
Thank you very much.
[All cough]
Someone has to be
a passenger pilot.
What's that you say?
I said, someone
has to be
a passenger pilot.
Can't hear you.
Forget it.
I'll go get the rest
of your shower door.
- Hey, thumbelina.
- I'm sorry, miss.
This area's out of bounds
to passengers.
- Um, I'm looking for mr.--
- goodbar?
Captain kemp.
Oh.
Uh, well he's in there.
He's...
Doing something
just at the moment,
but he won't be long.
[Joel laughs]
- Thank you.
- Hey, your calculator's on.
Oh boy, is she ever gonna--
where's the dry--
hey, what are you
looking at?
Oops.
What are you doing here?
I was looking for
a captain kemp.
This place is reserved
for space personnel only.
I'm sorry.
- Are you captain kemp?
- Will you go away?
Look at my stripes,
of course I'm captain kemp.
Go!
[P.a.]
Monorail to moon city
will depart
in seven minutes.
Oh. Hi, gumby.
Otto? Otto got killed?
Couple of days ago.
Yeah, we're dedicating
a locker room to him.
How?
Retro engines
failed on landing.
That's what I heard.
Went straight in.
Crunch.
Better put that thing outside
where people can read it.
Passengers wouldn't like it.
It would worry them.
Yeah, but to make it
a splash guard for a urinal?
Did you get the 12,000?
Here, I don't need it.
I already have pete rose.
Hey,
he flew the same
sort of space ferry
- you got, didn't he?
- Mm-hmm.
His was a little bit older,
that's all.
Little bit wiser.
Something to think about.
They dressed their stewardesses
like nazis.
Leaving right away,
mr. Hubbard.
- Magazine?
- Yes, it is.
Coffee? For you, sir?
He doesn't drink,
and he can't read.
But he still
has feelings, jeez.
They're so rich
they go to movies,
and they don't even
watch them.
- Trinie.
- Hello, bill.
You look great.
When'd you join the guard?
Right after I turned in
the von trapp family.
Same old me
on the inside, though.
Got a seat?
One up front
for the captain.
This is captain kemp,
ms. Taplin.
- You said--
- I'm always at a disadvantage
when I haven't
got any clothes on.
I never noticed it.
Well? What did you--
do you think I look
like a zucchini?
She looks like dot vader.
--Told me you'd fly over
to far side occasionally.
- Mm-hmm.
- I wondered
- if you know my brother.
- Gary larson.
Wally taplin. He's a miner.
No, no, I don't think
I know him.
He was supposed to meet me
at the space port.
He's probably waiting
at moon city.
Mm-hmm,
that's what the man said.
Don't you listen
to what the man says.
Your first time up here?
That would explain
the stupid hat.
Then I suggest
you look up front.
While I check out the rear.
Mm.
My god, it's so bleak.
No air. No vegetation.
One-sixth gravity.
Yeah, but on the good side,
there's no howie mandel.
--Fourteen days of night.
I suppose bleak is
as good a way as any
to describe it.
Yeah, and everybody
gets their own movie.
--Foreigners here.
We always will be.
Some are more foreign
than others, velvet-head.
Perhaps we should
never have come.
In the future,
bras will grow on the moon.
Cross my heart.
Hey, it's the original
space mountain.
What do you know? And look,
the line's still long.
The monument there
is where neil armstrong
landed back in 1969.
Course, that's just a model.
The real thing's
a lot bigger.
And the ice mines.
- The what?
- Ice mines.
They're layers of ice
a mile down.
Melt it into water,
and you drink it.
Break it into oxygen,
you breathe it.
Crush it and flavor it,
you got a slurpee.
D-cups as far
as the eye can see.
--Process oxygen.
When they die, we eat them.
There is nothing like it
anywhere else.
It's funny to think that,
with no air out there,
nobody can just
open up a window.
Oh, we've done that, but you
just have to be really fast.
Captain kemp, I'm afraid
we have no reservation
in the name
of mr. Wallace taplin.
Nor have we any messages
for a ms. Clementine taplin.
Yeah yeah, sure,
don't you have
to go make
some elfin cookies?
She looks like
an oompa loompa.
Well, it could be
he's just late.
The monorail doesn't go
any farther than moon city.
So he'd be coming by bug.
Bug?
It's a way you
get around up here.
They run convoys of them
over to far side--
it's lego moon base.
- It's a slow business.
- Vroom vroom.
Where's his claim?
Spectacle crater.
Well, the water's turned off
on the fountain,
so I can show you
where he is here.
- Right there.
- The nearest base
is far side five.
Now, that's
at least 2,000 miles
to moon city.
Six days by convoy.
That means
it takes longer to get
from one side of the moon
to the other.
Uh, no, but thanks
for playing.
That's right.
What about your spaceship?
Ferry.
It's only a moon ferry.
At least he's open about it.
-- In 20 minutes.
- I suppose--
- that's because
this is the future.
But I can send
a radio message, can't I?
- Uh-huh.
- To see if he's left?
Oh, no. Well,
you could've last week.
You see, we use a ring
of communication satellites
for relaying waves
around the curve,
but one was hit
by a meteorite.
So we're out of touch
with far side right now.
21st century.
It'll still be the same
in the 25th.
I suppose so.
Um, we're almost
walking off the set.
Would you mind, uh,
going the other way?
--As all that.
Splurge out.
Buy yourself a new outfit.
You'll feel better.
Oh, we'd better
get out of here, too.
Welcome to
the galaxy boutique.
- Can I help you?
- Look at that, a bare midriff.
On july 22nd, 1969,
a man first set foot
on the surface of the moon.
His name? Vince lombardi.
Oh, sorry,
it's neil armstrong.
This is our tribute
to astronaut armstrong
and the men who brought him
to the moon.
Crow will play the part
of neil armstrong.
That's one small step
for man.
- Save it!
- What? Oh.
Sorry.
Joel will play the part
of the second man on the moon,
edwin "buzz" aldrin,
and president
john f. kennedy.
I'll play the part
of mission control
and astronaut
michael collins
orbiting the moon.
- Okay.
- Ready? Okay.
Cue joel.
Ask not what your country
can do for you.
Rather what you can do
for your country.
It was 1962,
and a young president,
john f. kennedy,
makes a bold promise.
By the end of this decade,
we will send a man
safely to the moon
and return him safely home.
Uh, not bad, joel,
but you know, you sound
a little bit like
cliff from cheers.
[Crow strains]
- This is my big scene.
- "Not quite ten years later."
Thank you.
30 feet. Two and a half.
Picking up some dust.
30 seconds.
Contact light. Okay.
Engine stop.
We copy you down, eagle.
Houston,
tranquility base here.
The eagle has landed.
Roger, tranquility,
we copy you on the ground.
You got a bunch of guys
down here about to turn blue.
We're breathing again,
thanks a lot.
Thank you.
No? No. Okay,
I'm on the pad now.
I'm jumping off.
That's one small step
for a man.
One giant leap for mankind.
Ugh.
Okay, here I come.
I'm coming down out of
the lunar module.
Hey, joel, how come
your costume's not very good?
Well, I had to be the president
and buzz aldrin,
- so, okay? Jeez.
- Oh, okay.
Oh man, did--
do you have your keys?
I just locked ourselves
out of the lem.
No-- you what?
Oh, wow, that's one small
screw-up for you,
one giant screw-up for you.
- I'm gonna have to go--
- thus ends our project.
...find that thing.
What's that?
Whoa.
Yowza.
They're wearing othello
game pieces on their head.
Othello.
You know, I kind of
miss the moon, you guys.
I can see why.
Hey, crow, you can't
be wearing that, here.
Ow-- ow!
Oh, thank you.
Hey, it looks like liza minelli
and lola falana
had a garage sale.
I miss him, too.
He was a very good customer.
And a good man.
And a good pilot.
As pilots go,
he went.
Moon flower, double.
Uh, the name's bob,
if you don't mind.
It's an old-fashioned
pampas punch.
Pampers punch? Ick.
First one's on the house.
You didn't buy me a drink.
Nice bar, really crummy
atmosphere though.
[Bots laugh]
That one will live forever.
Lot of mileage there.
Still tastes like
distilled rocket fuel.
It is distilled rocket fuel.
That's easy for you to say.
How much it cost this week?
$35 a shot.
You see,
we're a long way from--
a long way from scotland,
I know.
Hey, pal,
I've got a small part.
Let me finish my own lines,
if you don't mind.
--But I haven't got
$35 a shot.
Isn't it about time
you got hungry?
A good point, michael.
And so the ground-space
engineer
passes ito the great unknown
unknown of joe's old time--
pizza-time theater.
Perhaps never to return.
He was otto von beck's
engineer
for a couple of years,
before he came to me.
Maybe he's just
glad to be alive.
Sure, all engineers
are crazy.
Hey, that's a pretty
broad statement, pal.
What did you call this?
Pampas punch?
No, it's bile. Why?
Tastes more like
tijuana brass polish.
Good one.
[Bots laugh]
It's moon zero mostel.
You know what
their answer is.
Hairpieces by
alexander calder.
They're doing the no-dance.
♪ No-no-no-no-no ♪
[Beeping]
Hey, you could've
just said "hello."
Hey, how are they making
that noise, joel?
That's no way to treat
a phone, friend.
I bought it a drink.
What more can a man do?
Well, maybe get it
some dinner.
A gentleman wants
a word with you.
You can tell him
to go to hell and stay.
Mr. Hubbard
wants to see you.
Old 100% hubbard?
L. Ron hubbard?
Old mother hubbard?
--He can go 100% to hell.
Let's just go
and see mr. Hubbard.
Convince me.
I'm convinced!
Oh, it's a gun.
I'm convinced.
Well, throw.
- Ooh, stupid.
- Oh brother.
Let's moon him, come on.
Honey, fix your dress.
Community chest.
Yeah.
Go to jail.
Move directly to jail.
Do not pass go.
Do not collect
$500.
Would you stop
sucking your thumb?
Oops.
What are you going to do?
I'll go to jail.
Now, while you are in jail,
I foreclose on the mortgage,
and I bankrupt you.
- Neat.
- Well, then I'm not gonna be
community chest anymore.
That leaves you
19,000 short.
Wow, nice pocket calculator.
Yeah, if you're a kangaroo.
And don't forget
the interest.
- I'm not interested
in interest.
- [Doorbell rings]
Hmm. That would be harry
with our guest.
Do you bathe?
Fourth floor,
tyrannical tycoons.
Loose women.
Works every time.
Don't anyone talk.
Oh, scotch.
Now, why didn't you say so?
Oh, I was concentrating
on my lines.
--Play with guns
on the surface floor.
One shot, and we'd all
have been breathing empty space.
So that's why you didn't
try to take it off me up there.
Well, there had to be
a reason, didn't there?
Not necessarily, sometimes
people take it for no reason.
Oh, your reputation didn't
exaggerate, mr. Kemp.
Perhaps I should apologize
for sending a man like harry--
no, I'm just wild
about harry.
--First man on mars.
Is that him?
Sweetener?
A long time ago.
And now you're flying
a ten-year-old space ferry
and salvaging dead satellites
to sell to the junkyards.
Don't talk about sarah
that way.
--Hardly.
Will you stop fiddling
with that thing?
- Eh.
- But I've never
been to switzerland.
Well, the only thing
worth seeing are the banks.
Grr.
I think you knew
otto von beck.
An otto on the surface
of the moon?
It'll never work.
And I believe you are
the only other pilot
on the moon
with a ship for charter.
Otto was going
to do a little job for me.
Now.
Now?
- Now?
- Do you know
asteroids, mr. Kemp?
- Sure, I have atari.
- The remains of a planet
which exploded
or was never formed.
Some of them grains of dust,
some the size
of small moons.
And everything in between.
Hundreds of--
you're making a spectacle
out of yourself.
Sorry.
Doesn't he look like
the head of k.A.O.S?
Yeah, I was just
thinking that.
Some never named,
never charted.
Bernie koppel?
The orphans of
the solar system, mr. Kemp.
The guy from mad girl.
Is that how it works?
You can't set up
a mine on an asteroid.
Cost of flying
the equipment up.
The supplies,
bringing the ore back.
It never pays.
Not mine it, mr. Kemp.
Land it on the moon.
Land it?
You mean crash it,
and that's
against the law
in a big way.
He's right,
just ask john landis.
--Pilot might
drop it on moon city.
Well, we don't
do things that way.
You would have the results
of two years' research
to help you.
- We would--
- good lord, he's ugly.
--Experienced
pilot on the moon.
He's so immense.
So what's so special
about one asteroid?
It's worth bonus points.
You go on to the next screen.
--When you get there,
so I may as well tell you now.
Whitsun.
I don't even know my name.
Too small to have
either a name or a number.
The asteroid was
first photographed in 1998
when it happened to pass
close to the earth.
But it was never
investigated or plotted.
Until two years ago.
This film was taken
by mr. Hubbard's
astronomical division.
I'm sorry,
that's my gallstone.
60 feet by 30 by 30,
estimated mass,
approximately 6,000 tons.
Heavy.
This is me playing breakout.
Do you read spectrograms,
mr. Kemp?
Some of the easy ones.
This looks like aluminum.
That's very good.
It's quite similar
to aluminum.
- But an aluminum--
- is that richard kiel's
stupider brother?
--The heart
of an exploding planet
hundreds of millions
of years ago.
What is the name again,
whitsun?
A ceramic crystalline form
of corundum-aluminum oxide.
Or something like that.
Sapphire, mr. Kemp.
I love sapphire.
- Sapphire.
- She's great.
6,000 tons
of gemstone sapphire.
Okay.
That's what's so special
about this asteroid.
Well, that's my birthstone.
I'll do it.
Well?
Sounds like a nice,
profitable idea.
But it's still
against the law.
So's your forehead, though.
We understand that you're
already in trouble with the law.
- Huh?
--The bureau
wants to ground you.
Oh, come now, whitsun.
That's no way
to treat our guest.
Yeah, he's too old
for grounding.
Mr. Kemp must be
entirely free
to make up his own mind.
Which is great for him.
And just suppose I freely
make up my mind to come in.
What do I get out of it?
Don pardo, show him
what he'll win.
A brand new space ferry.
- Hello.
- Could come in handy.
Order one tomorrow.
But at that price,
you could get your own ship.
Get your own crew.
But not secretly.
You see, someone like myself
starts to outfit
an expedition into space,
well, it attracts
questions, snoopers.
Snoopers and blabbers!
Investigations
from the bureau.
But you.
You just pop off into space
on one of your--
hey!
--No questions asked.
And a few days later,
an asteroid just happens
to land on the far side
of the moon.
And since nobody's
bothered to plot it,
- nobody can say that--
- oh, thank you, vidal sassoon.
I don't look good,
and you don't look good.
Flight a-e-3
will lift off--
hey, her boots
are eating her.
Will passengers please
it's her tribute
to bronco nagurski.
- You're leaving again
pretty quickly.
- She was in
yards of leather, I think.
Us un-salaried workers
have to keep working.
- [All] Ouch.
- That looks like
quite a heavy load
you have there.
What is it?
Oh, some experimental
propulsion equipment
I want to test in space.
Sure, did you get it from
a honeymoon catalogue?
Section 47-c, paragraph one.
No information about commercial
or industrial secrets
need be disclosed
without the authority
of the moon court warrant.
But I'm paraphrasing,
of course.
There's more than one way
to skin a cat.
Everyone says that, but no one
ever tells me the other way.
Good luck, bill.
You have to marry
that girl, bill.
What do you mean, "have to"?
It might be better than
her throw you in jail.
Looks like these guys
got suited up
for a foosball game.
--Marry her anyway.
You gotta marry her, bill.
She's got
the wedding bell blues.
Up up and away.
I'll just throw this
back here.
Ah, I'm intrinsically evil.
And I've got a new jogging suit
I'm showing off.
--Of earth express.
We understand it's a sight
no tourist should miss.
When would you
be ready to lift-off?
Yes, this time,
we can pay the bill, okay?
[All] Okay, meester fawlty.
The pump-valve
on number two.
We are ready now.
Passengers?
He's got a computer
in that briefcase.
- And he's not afraid
to use it.
- Duck!
--With the heavy work.
I'll get over there.
That's mr. Kaminski,
isn't it?
Your engineer?
What nationality is he?
He's from barcelona.
That wasn't quite
what I asked.
We're all foreigners
up here.
Some more than others.
Ready to go?
Without the pistol, please.
You don't take this
off me twice.
Then the trip's off.
If that thing
goes off in the ship,
we'd never get back
to explain why.
Give it to me, harry.
But I feel totally naked
without it.
It's my only accessory.
Give him the pearl
earrings too, harry.
Let's hope we all have
a profitable trip.
Let you know
in about four days.
Pow, sluggo.
Shut up.
That's the coffee.
That should be ready
in a minute or two.
Okay, we're pressurized.
You can take your helmets off.
Just kidding.
Whitsun,
I want the main course
exactly 90 seconds
after blastoff.
You are a hungry little guy.
Are we letting him navigate?
He's got a better computer
than we have.
- Can he use it?
- He figures that counting
miles per hour
isn't so different
than dollars per second.
As long as he remembers
you can't get
miles per hour on credit.
I love your wry, naive wit,
my european friend.
--Zero two.
Request takeoff clearance.
Round trip, no landing away,
as usual.
First class or coach?
Smoking or non?
Zero two, you're clear.
Mars express
due in 20 minutes.
But are we clear?
Zero two.
I'll try to miss him. Out.
They really did a great job
of antiquing that ship.
Slap in the road tape, dude,
and get the j.D.
From under the seat.
Hey, melon-head,
get off my foot.
Travels with
roller derby queens.
It's great.
Oh, it's esther williams.
She's in a fish bowl.
Got that course yet,
whitsun?
Relative to the elliptic,
I want a course
of alpha 351,
meter 179,
speed 17,500.
Then a sherry, medium dry.
--As if he knows.
It does, doesn't it?
- Do you think he means--
- woop woop! Woop woop!
Oh, more or less, I suppose.
I hope it's not
too difficult for you.
Not at all, mr. Whitsun.
Well, if you have it
on beta-graph,
I hope I can make
the situation clear to you.
It's over there.
Well, it's not new,
but I think it works.
Are we talking about
the same thing here?
Would you turn off
"peter and the wolf," please?
The earth, the moon
revolving around it.
Now, this year, this week,
the asteroid is making
its closest approach to the moon
since 1998 on this course.
It's the closest approach
since I grew
my bushy-wushy sideburns.
--Adjust and adjust here.
45 hours from now.
The importance
of being earnest.
That's where I saw him.
A gentleman caller,
actually,
but these rockets,
as I was saying.
--Will change to this orbit.
You will observe
that its speed
relative to the moon
is quite slow.
And that it is only visible
from far side.
The radar stations
on near side cannot see it.
You appreciate
the importance of this.
Well, if they could,
we'd be in jail
- the moment we got back.
- Exactly.
Have you ever been in jail?
You'd like it quite a lot.
--The asteroid will
have come to within
10,000 miles of the moon.
We shall return to it,
take new measurements,
reset the engines,
and fire them again.
- Am I boring you?
- The asteroid lands
on the moon.
Crunch. I get the picture.
[Indistinct]...
From far side five!
Huh?
Well, I'm glad they know
what she said.
Hey, there's a sell
at penney's.
Hide the garnishes, quick!
All the knick-knacks
gotta be moved.
Sure are a shiny bunch.
Hey, it's randolph mantooth.
Sorry, I thought were--
is that rayon
they're wearing?
Naugahyde!
Hey, it's hee-haw 1999.
Pretty soon they'll get
those big foam
"we're number one" hands.
Anybody know
where a guy can get
some armor-all around here?
Hey, it's the same dance
with different hats,
but it's a completely
different experience.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Someone didn't
finish your haircut.
Oh my. I'm in love.
Excuse me again,
but do you know
mr. Wallace taplin?
Wally? Yes, I know wally.
Seems like
the benny hill show.
Not well enough, apparently.
Are you a friend of his?
- No, I'm his sister.
- That's a great relief.
Was he on this convoy?
Well, if he was,
I didn't see him.
Well, what was his handle?
--Sit down, take a drink?
Yes, yes, join us. Come on.
Three more
rocket fuels, please.
And an air freshener.
You know, their rocket fuel
contains no ethanol.
--Haven't seen wally in,
oh, maybe four months.
Hand-check.
- You're just up from earth.
- Yeah.
Have you tried radioing him?
Of course, you can't.
That satellite's out,
isn't it?
You'd think they'd have
decent communications
here on the moon.
No government ever spent
one dollar till they lost five.
- Yeah, five--
- hey, it's buffalo bob!
--Way we are
around the back there.
Why are they all english?
Cheese it,
it's the gator babe!
'Cause they're
the only ones pale enough
to simulate being
out of the direct sunlight.
Any news, ms. Taplin?
Something must have
happened to him.
Nobody's seen him
for months.
Well, he may have
just missed the convoy.
I love that woman.
Out at far side five.
Yes, that's--
oh, we'd better go.
- I've never known--
- come on, you guys.
I wanna stay
and watch my babe.
--Want any help,
except now.
You know, you guys,
I was just thinking
about that kind of dumb
moon-opoly joke
they got in there.
It's just a stupid pun,
but, you know,
in the future,
the games we play now
are gonna be a lot different
with the future element
involved, you know.
Like twister will probably
be played on your tongue.
Uh, yeah, and nintendo
would be moon-tendo.
With the super lunar
mario brothers.
- It's possible.
- Well, risk is riskier.
Right, and sorry will seem
to be the hardest game.
And, uh, say you're
playing clue,
and the answer
might be colonel mustard
in the command module
with laser bolos.
'Cause it's a spaceship.
Parcheesi
will be greencheesi.
Skittle-bowl
will be the same,
but it will take
even longer to set up
because of no gravity.
Chutes and ladders
is replaced by vacuum tubes,
you know, like on the jetsons,
'cause that's the only way
they can get around
from place to place.
Candyland's the same,
but you should see
the new flavors they've got.
Right.
Kaboom! Is called
don't smoke on the ship
because it's
an oxygen-rich atmosphere,
and you could blow up,
and that would be...
- Bad.
- Right, and they won't
have mice,
because they'll need
to use them for research.
- So no mouse trap. Right.
- You know, you can't
play mouse trap.
Etch-a-sketch will
finally be able to draw
curved lines, I bet.
Scruples aren't around anymore
because people won't have any.
Trivial pursuit will be
trivial moon suit
yeah, now win, lose, or draw
is called
win, lose, and draw oxygen.
Right.
Password has been replaced
by games higher in fiber.
Well, I got a game form my past
that's in my present,
and I think we'll keep
going into the future.
You know how it works, guys,
it's rock 'em sock 'em robots.
[Bots scream]
All right, I knocked
his block off.
But you can push it back down,
and it's--
whoa, movie sign!
Let's go!
Three... two...
Give her the works-- cut!
Don't rock 'em sock 'em us
any more.
- Stop it.
- Hey, let me at him.
Let me at him.
- Come on, you guys.
- I'll murder him.
Break it up.
A 6,000 ton jewel.
How would you
like to meet the broad
who could hang that
around her neck?
Uh, she's probably
got a boyfriend.
What do you think
of being in space?
Hey, it's major kong.
Is that what they call
a crotch-rocket?
Wow, I never knew
outer space was so well-lit.
In space, no one
can hear you yawn.
--Exactly do you
want this attached?
- On the cradle.
- Treat it gently.
This is number three.
This is liable to go off
early as late.
Fasten your safety line,
harry.
I'll go down and get the leads
from the other engines.
Hey, get some tape
while you're at it.
And bring me back a soda.
Anything but mr. Pibb.
Joel, isn't that the same shot
done upside-down?
Well, kind of.
What they do is
they turn
the camera over twice,
and they shoot it backwards
at high-speed into a mirror.
Oh. Seems like it'd be easier
to just shoot it upside-down.
Yeah, probably.
Now, if each engine is set
for exactly...
100,000 pounds thrust,
- then--
- hey, it's a meat scale.
Maybe he's trying
to price that boulder.
Looks pretty well marbled.
Quarter-inch trim.
--One hour and 18 minutes.
If number three
goes off right on time.
If it doesn't, it'll ruin
the whole operation.
Yeah, but if it does,
it'll work.
If it doesn't, just do it.
--So do all the rest.
Shouldn't they have figured
all this out on the ship?
I'll stay here
and give it a thump
when you give me
the countdown.
When they do fire,
she won't make
like a spaceship,
but she'll be
building up thrust.
- Will you be okay?
- Provided I get off
in the first
ten seconds, yes.
All right.
Are you sure you'll be
all right, mr. Kemp?
You take care of your
calculations.
I'll take care of myself.
But let's just try
to work together, okay?
- Thank you for asking anyway.
- Grr.
My pleasure, glad to do it.
Let's do lunch.
Don't lose
your happy thoughts.
Can't tell if they're just
dangling from wires there.
They look like bait.
♪ It's not easy
being green ♪
I'm curious but yellow.
Ah, frog and a bear,
together again.
Wocka wocka wocka!
What?
Here's the meat scale
you ordered.
Yeah, where's my mr. Pibb,
though?
Oops.
Hey.
See that?
Means absolutely nothing.
15 seconds, mr. Kemp.
Not by my watch.
- Ten...
- Thirteen.
- Nine...
- Eight.
- Eight...
- Two million.
- 49.
- Seven.
- One, three,
- five.
- Hut hut hike!
- Four.
- 867-5309.
- Two...
- One.
- Thump. Thump!
Space sounds
by chuck mangione.
Yahoo.
A real yahoo.
You've got five seconds
to get free.
Five, four, three...
Phew.
Hey, it looks like
his stone passed him.
I would've
he would've ended up
in his socks.
You know, at least
he would've died with
his birthstone, though.
Are you okay, bill?
Oh, I've been better.
Only it's a little lonely
out here.
Are you walking home,
or would you like a lift?
I think I'll take a lift.
Have you back down there
before you know it.
Try to make it
before the bar shuts.
Wow, they're so versatile.
It's kind of like
swan lake a-go-go.
When does wonder boy reckon
we should go out again?
Three days.
According to his
box of tricks.
Want a drink?
Later. I am going to eat.
They made some extra cash
by selling this set
to donny and marie.
A double moon flower
please, len.
In a dirty space tumbler.
Buffalo stampede.
Is that norm crosby?
Or corm nosby.
There's a lady been asking for
you for the past couple of days.
Space get-up
works every time.
What's she drinking?
- Green mary.
- What?
Rocket fuel
and cabbage juice.
And a shot of bile.
Which takes the taste away
from which?
I don't know.
I only serve it.
And take your money.
Think he tips himself
out of that?
I don't know.
He's gonna have to file
a chapter 13 with
all those moon drinks.
Well, you're paying
for the garnishes.
Yeah.
Hey, how's the egg coming?
Found your brother yet?
No.
Not on the convoy?
Not on two convoys.
And nobody seems to have seen
him in nearly four months.
Well, far side is
a big place.
You just don't
go visiting someone
when it's a hundred miles
of rough country
and in a moon bug, which--
hey, florence henderson
hairdo.
Looks like she did it
with wesson oil.
Mr. Kemp, do you know anything
about moon mining laws?
Mm, a little.
Can you explain
the two-year rule?
Well, you got a claim
for two years,
and if you haven't
found anything
at the end of that time,
you get thrown out.
Somebody else gets it.
There's quite
a waiting list.
Seems a bit unfair.
Maybe, but the moon costs
a lot of money to get started.
And they can't have
people just
digging holes
and not finding anything.
Well, unless they
call them craters.
--Brother had his claim?
- Two years--
in three days' time.
- Yeah, well, uh,
who's got the deed
on the forehead?
That's what
I'd like to know.
--Cable,
that's why I'm up here.
Well, you'd better tell him
to get over here and prove it.
- Before he loses his claim.
- I radioed.
He's talking to a lady.
But the convoys...
No, they wouldn't
be quick enough.
Mr. Kemp, will you
fly me over there?
I don't know,
how fast do you go?
I know I haven't
got $10,000 on me now.
But if wally's
found something,
we'll pay you back
as soon as we're selling it.
I couldn't land
on your brother's claim.
- That would hurt.
- It's much too rough country.
But we could go
to far side five.
It's a 24-hour ride
in a bug from there.
You can owe it to me.
Yeah, what the hell,
I'm nearly rich anyway.
Let's have another drink.
Uh, can't I finish
the one I've got?
Len, I'd like two more
of whatever they are.
Sewage bilge.
You weren't thinking of taking
the young lady for a ride,
were you, mr. Kemp?
I'm a pilot for hire.
You're already hired.
Drop her.
It'll only be
a three day trip.
I'll be back in time.
That's what
the skipper said.
Drop her.
- That would hurt her.
- You seem to have your hand
on me.
I'm no doctor,
but I'm pretty sure
you got your hand on me.
--Really owns.
Hey, watch the slush puppie
machine.
If we're gonna play...
We're gonna play
by my rules.
Yeah, but nobody knows
what your rules are.
Always have your hair cut
by a machine.
And I always look like
dennis hopper.
Ooh, he gave him a snuggie.
In space, no one
can hear a wedgie.
Look out, big bird!
Oh, magic screen.
Oh, he should've
seen that coming.
Picked up a spare.
Touchdown in 17 minutes.
Be careful,
we've just gone weightless.
I know.
Just like the moon express.
Though your ship
is different in other ways.
You mean no toilet paper?
Yeah, sorry about that.
You are in for a nice, long
night drive in a moon-bug.
Just built for two.
I'll stay with the ship
and give her a sprinkling.
And get some sleep.
And give her a sprinkling.
Approaching re-entry point.
That's our cue, doll-face.
Cool.
Hey, could you turn down
that stereo?
The old west.
In space,
no one can art-direct.
--Haven't seen
wally here in, oh,
must be nearly
four months by now.
We tried to radio him
a couple of times.
But it's always chancy
in the mountain country.
How about relaying it?
Well, I could
ask nick hunter
to ask louis grenier
to ask tad connell
to pass on a message.
- But--
- but they're all dead.
It'd be silly.
--Kidney trouble
the last fortnight.
And I know that nick
went over to moon city
on the last convoy.
- On the other hand--
- do I need to know this?
We might be able
to contact bill wirter.
Oh, no.
He's off-radio for
the next couple of days.
Sorry, there doesn't
seem to be any way.
Well, when you
didn't hear from him,
didn't you think
of declaring an emergency?
Do you think
this permanent wave
is a good idea for my hair?
Looks like big boy.
The satellite's
only been dead for 12 days.
I know that, but...
Nobody dies slowly
on the moon.
You know that.
Hmm, well,
can I take a bug, then?
Well, one's out.
- I said "bug light."
- I was hoping to do an overhaul
on the other.
I'd need
a thousand dollars deposit.
Oh, I have that in my shoe.
Your odor-eater.
Thank you very much.
I'm afraid you're
over your credit limit.
Do you have
a dr. Scholl's pad on you?
Is it ready?
As ready as she'll ever be.
I guess
she'll get you there.
And back?
Sure do hope so.
Climb aboard.
Oh man, she's cherry, man.
Put on some
thrush glasspacks, man.
He's got some twin headers
with a .44 barrel.
Screams.
- The van's pretty nice, too.
- Uh, move over.
Unless you want to drive.
Hey, how many girls
have you had in your moon bug?
Well, if you've gotta go,
you'd better do it now.
How do you like my new
"moon sounds" tape
by philip glass?
Hey, I know,
let's sing car songs.
You know, like
the wiener-man song, yeah.
♪ I know a wiener man ♪
♪ he owns a hot dog stand ♪
♪ he-- sorry.
How about another one?
And so they set out
in the wiener car in search
of the giant kielbasa.
Huh, we're out of gas.
Hey, there's
jacques cousteau.
I'm sorry, but this
is a part of the moon
that tourists
don't usually see.
If we pull the wrong lever
out here,
there's no guarantee
we'll even be found.
I'm sorry.
But I'm not a tourist,
mr. Kemp.
I'm here to stay and work
with my brother.
I know, it's
a little bit rough now,
but it'll be better
when we fall in love
later in the picture.
I understand.
How long does it stay dark?
- All night.
- It'll be...
...sun-up in 40 hours.
So that's like
a hundred hours.
200 degrees below zero.
And up above boiling point
when the sun's out.
Don't worry,
these bugs have efficient
heating and cooling
systems.
We've always
got the moon suits.
Yeah, I guess
if I had to do it over,
I'd probably buy foreign.
I see what you mean about
we'll always be foreigners.
No, I said I'd buy foreign.
Why'd your brother
pick this end of the moon?
He didn't, it was the only claim
left when he got here.
That figures.
What was he mining on earth?
Gold. Some silver.
Last thing he found
was copper up in montana.
Sold out cheap
to a big company.
He always thinks there'll be
a bigger and better strike
over the next hill.
He came over a big hill
this time.
- Funny.
- Your father?
He blew himself up
five years ago.
Dynamiting for emeralds
in the andes.
- And your mom?
- I hardly knew him.
He was always off somewhere,
digging a new hole
over a new hill.
You're the bill kemp
who was the first man on mars.
That's right.
That's funny,
meeting you like this.
Driving a hired moon bug?
No.
I can remember
when we got the news
that you'd landed on mars.
I was just
a schoolgirl then.
And I wasn't very interested
in space-travel.
Okay, okay.
Rub it in, I'm old.
Then the astronomy teacher
showed us mars one night.
He told us how far it was.
It still is.
I remember your name
from then.
The man who'd
flown a spaceship
for 40 million miles.
Okay, you're 12, I'm 100.
I get it already.
Oh, I could still recite you
the names of the crew.
That's more than I could.
You ever think about renting out
your forehead for advertising?
Why'd you give it up?
Exploring.
It gave me up.
After mars and jack harvey
got on venus,
the corporation decided
that passengers
was where the money was.
Sure, it would've taken
some money
and some new inventions, too,
to get to mercury and...
Jupiter's moons.
Jupiter, that's a planet,
isn't it?
Anyway, I wasn't
a passenger pilot,
so I quit.
Okay, I lied. They got me
on a morals charge.
- I understand.
- You do?
Chinese good for you?
- Hey, it's a souvenir bank.
- Always something
over the next hill.
- I know.
- And always on borrowed money.
But there is something
over the hill.
That's the trouble
for a woman.
All space travel
is just a big way
of getting out of the house
on a saturday evening.
Well, if you don't have
anything better to do.
And we sure don't.
♪ I wanna be
his wiener wife ♪
♪ I wanna join
his wiener life ♪
Hey, nice steps.
Looks like they should have
boxing gloves at the end of 'em.
Looks like they're
kind of crawling out
of the tupperware orange.
Now, those suits
are different colors
so you can tell who's who.
If she gets confused,
she should just remember
that she's her.
Huh?
Uh, they left
their dome light on.
Someone's gonna
have to get a jump-start.
Triple-a's even gonna
charge 'em for that one.
Oh, brother.
Her brother lived
in a porta-potty.
Wow, look at it in there.
Your brother
was really a slob.
Hey, is there air
coming out of your suit,
or are you playing
a trumpet?
Skin sample.
Looks valuable.
Wish I had me
one of them plows.
--Found something.
Two driveways.
- Where are you?
- Around the corner.
Don't wander off.
You've gotta stay in sight.
I'm sorry.
A set-up like that is bound
to scare off trick-or-treaters.
- Do you know what this is?
- A piece of rock.
Looks like your brother's
kneecap.
With a vein of nickel in it,
and a very rich one.
Wally did find something.
Are you sure?
I know a little
about geology.
Well, we all know
a little bit.
Where could he have gone?
Not far, or he would've
taken his bug-dozer.
Now just how disappointed
would you be
if you never saw
your brother alive again?
Look, there's someone there!
Oh, him, he's always there.
It's a space lawn jockey.
Everyone's got 'em at
the end of their driveway.
Now, remember, there
will be three of us now.
And you're the one
that's you,
in the blue, all right?
Oh, he's lost weight.
He looked much better heavy.
I suppose he just
made a mistake.
He managed for two years
without making one.
And he didn't
puncture his suit.
He had to have oxygen
to look like--
to go as he did.
One full. One empty.
Which one
do you think he used?
Just a stupid mistake.
Well, I bet
he'll never do it again.
Let's use our precious oxygen
and bury him.
See this? It's his nintendo.
He would've
wanted me to have it.
Well, if he'd have known me.
I'm keeping it.
Honey, cookies are done.
Hold it.
Oops.
Looks like we got company.
It's the unwelcome wagon.
You out there,
identify yourselves.
Okay, will this help?
They call me shooter.
Get down.
Damn moon goons!
Hey, they come in
great flavors, too.
There's raspberry red,
burnt umber,
and, of course, chartreuse.
Oh, man, and I bet that moon
buggy was on his card, too.
Excuse me, I'm nervous.
I'm sorry,
you'll have to excuse me.
We're on telephone now.
They can't hear us, but don't
say anything on radio.
- They're picking it all up.
- Is there a seven-second delay?
Can I swear?
Come on out, both of you,
or we'll drill you like a sieve.
What kind of sieve?
That ought to keep them busy.
Don't shoot.
The girl's hurt.
You've gotta help me.
Does this help?
Timpani gun.
Works every time.
Well, you got lime green.
Just raspberry red
and lemon yellow to go.
But remember,
trix are for kids.
Now just remember,
they're the guys in color.
There's another way out.
Hey, there's
a barracuda in here.
If we don't die, you wanna
catch a movie or something?
I mean, if you're not alive,
I totally understand.
It won't hurt my feelings
or anything.
Back in the caves.
Hey, plow your driveway,
mister?
Jeez.
Oh, he killed
a blow-up doll.
Soup's on, he said flatly.
Looks like he's going after
a crack house.
Wow, lawn and garden
attachments.
That guy's got
all the candy.
Uh, just take a little
off the torso, please.
This is like
a bad music festival.
Hey, shut the door.
What, are you born in a vacuum?
Hey, slippery guy,
he's playing possum.
Told you.
- Whoops.
- [Man pants]
Hey. Hurt, little fella?
Quickly, give me
your brother's pack.
How do I know it's you?
I'm wearing white,
you idiot!
What good is it
if they're on the moon
if they just re-enact
the atrocities from earth?
That's a good
seal impression.
This one's going
back to the store.
- Yes?
- I think I may just put on
the waste container.
Whatever's in here,
it isn't air.
How do we get out of here?
Our bug's ridden off.
Let's try this one.
Yeah, it's got
lawn attachments
and a blaupunkt stereo.
Factory air. The works.
Oh man, it smells like
a mushroom factory in here.
Those guys were really evil.
Leave your suit on.
It's 200 degrees
below zero in here.
What's the wind chill,
though?
Can't we turn
the heating on?
Oh, it's all shot to hell.
What, the plot?
And we've only got power
for about 150 miles.
But not for heating
and cooling as well.
We'll have to stay
in our suits all the way.
We can't do that either.
Our charges won't last
more than a few hours.
150 miles.
- Let's beat it.
- That's over 200 miles--
my charge is
wearing out, too.
--But this thing's built
to go over mountains.
Oh, he always says that
when he gets in trouble
and gets lost.
Boy, servo,
what a great movie.
Great actresses, too.
I like the babe
with the great haircut.
The one with the eddie munster
page boy look?
Nah, I like
the gator-headed chick.
The one with the eel-skin
skull cap? No way.
- Ugh.
- Hey, watch it!
You're talking about
the woman I love here.
She's got style.
She's got looks.
She's got a .45
strapped to each thigh,
and she knows
how to use 'em.
She's a darn sight
better than
that twiggy little stick-woman
you have your eyes on.
Hey, what are you saying?
All I'm saying is that
you little thin-limbed
scrawny empty-headed types
seem to stick together
so well.
You wanna piece of me?
I'm standing right here.
When this is over, you and me
going round and round.
Botto-á-botto.
Hey, come on, you guys.
What's going on?
Break it up here.
- What's the problem?
- Hey, stay out of this, joel.
This is between me
and the fireplug.
That's it, that's it!
Stand back, joel!
You're using my oxygen!
Come on, let's go.
Listen, you guys,
if there's gonna be a fight,
we're gonna do it my way.
Not that--
I'll... get...
You...
I want your head...
On a pla-- ah!...
[Bots shout]
Stay out of this...
Joel...
Turn it off!...
Whoa!
Kids, when you got a beef,
don't take the law
into your own hands.
Take it to zero-g.
Anti-gravity.
It's not just
for breakfast anymore.
We're going to make it.
What, are they driving
through snack canyon?
Feh on you.
This is where it starts.
It'll take
a little time yet.
Automatic pilot.
Boy, I must have
the zactlies.
My suit's pretty steamy.
You'd better turn
your insulation off
to save the last
of the charge.
We might need it later on.
Ow, there's hair back there.
How far now?
About 80 miles.
It looks as though
the worst is over.
Seems pretty flat from here.
Just when we need the shade.
Take off your moon suit.
He asked her, he asked her!
Boy, I wish I was him.
What're you gonna do now?
Now that you're not gonna
work with your brother.
- I'm going to disneyworld.
- Back to earth?
Uh, who said she's not
working with her brother?
Her brother's dead.
Any jobs going for a good
spaceshipping clerk up here?
- Oh.
- Could be.
That's a bad thing.
Thanks.
Oh, that feels good, thanks.
I'm sorry I dragged you
into all of this.
I'm not.
It'd be a bit silly
for bill kemp
to die just here.
On the moon.
After all the places
you've been, I mean.
It'd be a bit silly for
bill kemp to die anyplace,
as far as I'm concerned.
So sit down,
and start telling me
how much farther we have to go.
Gotta get past
his attitude first.
Whoa, joel, give me a hand,
I'm shorting out here--
- what is this?
- Oh, it's just the film.
- Don't worry, servo.
- Focus!
Whoo.
Oh, honey, could you put
some more water on those rocks?
Whoo, nothing better
than this.
- This is the life.
- Is there any water left?
Just the gallons
you're putting out.
Chinese again.
- That's my specimen.
- It's damn near boiling.
Well? What's the matter?
- Yowza.
- Nothing from where
I'm standing.
[Crow whistles]
Not a thing.
I knew there had to be
a good part of this movie.
If it gets any hotter,
I'll very likely
take the rest of it off.
Hey, pray for heat, huh?
[Bots] Yeah.
[Bots buzz]
How much farther?
Well, the script says
a few more miles.
Only a few miles.
How many few?
I don't know. Seven? Ten?
- Which is it? Seven or ten?
- ♪♪ [trumpet]
I'm sorry, but seven means
we might make it.
- Ten means we won't.
- What's the trumpet mean?
Look, we've got power
for another couple of miles.
Then we walk.
We've got an hour's
insulation charge
left in the suits.
Shut up that jazz combo.
I'm nervous enough as it is.
The overheating has melted
the pressure flood.
I only hope--
quick! Into your suit.
Oh, damn, I thought we were
taking the suits off.
Suicide door.
Those exploder boats
come in handy.
Of course
it's gonna explode.
They parked over a campfire.
Quick, in the crack.
Wait! Oh, the jazz combo
was still in there.
The day the music died.
Guess they
won't try that again.
Who decided free-form jazz
was the right thing
for the soundtrack?
Look!
It's far side five. Come on.
They make a great burger.
Let's beat cheeks.
All right, bill.
- You're under arrest.
- Beat the rush.
Fine.
Now, has anybody got
a nice, cool drink?
Don't say hi.
Hope he likes rocket fuel.
She just flopped down
on that formica.
--Suddenly appeared.
She always gets
her man, bill.
Well, you've really been
running up an account
this time.
Yeah, and you're the one
with the funny skull.
--Breach the pressure
of an outside room.
Malicious damage
to hotel property.
Ms. Taplin's brother
has been murdered out there.
Come on.
You can do better than that.
Yes, well, three other
characters got killed,
but I did that myself.
When you get into trouble,
you really jump off
the top board, don't you.
She's really got sort of
a julie andrews quality,
- doesn't she?
- Yeah, I think she got
that skull cap
from thoroughly modern millie.
One thing we can check
right now.
Wally taplin was killed
with one of these.
Tell me what you think
it smells like.
- Cheese balls.
- Uh, pine forest?
- Watermelon?
- Wet canvas?
Just one sniff.
Could be cyanide.
Cyanide? That's my favorite.
Funny, I just took it off
my own suit.
Smells like me.
And I didn't like
that wet canvas crack either.
--Fresh air to me.
But you thought
it was cyanide.
Now, you sold him
his air bottles.
You sell all air bottles
around here.
Uh, yeah,
but I distinctly remember
not selling that air bottle.
You'd better answer him.
They-- they made me.
They wanted taplin's claim.
It was due to expire!
It seems
they'd found something.
And they had to have it.
What for?
- Tell him.
- To land an asteroid on it.
Pizza's ready.
It's a brand new car!
Mr. Hubbard,
they found out about it.
You've got to get me
off the moon.
[Crow as klink]
Hogan, I wouldn't say any more
about that if I were you.
You've reached
the confession stage.
And in front of
the bureau of investigation.
Is that wrong?
Should I have not done that?
I'm glad we got here
on time, mr. Kemp.
I was afraid
some of my associates--
never trust a man
with a collar
made of shinyl vinyl.
--This project and would have
disposed of you.
They tried.
Really? All three of them?
All three.
Even raspberry red?
I really did
underestimate you,
mr. Kemp.
So we're three men
short, then.
We should make
a note to engage.
Mr. Hubbard?
You're under arrest.
I don't think so.
Do you, harry?
Uh, I'm sorry, I was
dreaming about rabbits.
Let me get this straight.
You got that louse
to murder my brother
just so that you could have
a place to land an asteroid?
Uh, in a nutshell, yeah.
Oh!
Speaking of nutshells.
Oh, well, I'll get that.
That's okay, not a problem.
Mr. Kent, please.
Don't get yourself killed
- unnecessarily.
- Uh, okay.
Hey, are those french cuffs?
I suppose I look
rather silly to you, bill.
Don't think...
I'm gonna be able to get you
out of this one.
- This time, bill.
- Don't talk, liz.
I'm gonna--
gonna miss you, bill.
Even the--
the rows were good.
Bury my turtle hat
at wounded knee.
We're quite safe, sir.
None of the shots
pierced the dome.
Yes, well, I believe
we need to take off
for the asteroid
in just under one hour.
If you think I'm gonna
land that thing
for you now, you're--
but I do.
Whitsun,
when was the last time
we abandoned a project
without any profit?
- Stonehenge.
- Oh, yes, I remember.
There was no oil there,
was there?
- No, sir.
- No, but there is sapphire
in this asteroid,
mr. Kemp, so...
If she's dead,
I could scoop her out
and make a terrarium
out of her.
Somebody say something.
Harry.
Shoot the young lady.
Uh, which one?
The one that's not dead,
you idiot!
Oh, yeah-yeah-yeah.
Right, right.
All right, okay, don't move.
That's better.
Much.
$200,000
in the gem market.
You kids be careful
down there.
--For full retro effect.
We can arrange that
by firing two engines early.
One of them will
have to be number three.
Just remember that.
- Yeah-yeah-yeah, I knew that.
- --Anticipated that.
Got my gum back.
Number three controls
the firing of the others.
Come out here,
where the boyfriend
can see you, love.
Sort of encourage him
in his work.
That's it, bill.
Keep it up, buddy.
You're looking great.
--Four and seven minutes,
it'll still land
on the plain.
Now, could someone get me
a medium sherry?
Very nice one? Thank you.
If I'm going
to stay down here
and thump
number three again--
- I'll need a magazine.
- I'll need a long line.
Like a soliloquy
or a monologue?
Ms. Taplin?
They're up in
the passenger deck.
Well, should I make coffee too,
mr. Hefner?
This is one of my
best escape tricks ever.
I chain myself
to this ladder, see?
And then-- oh, hi.
What can I do?
Into the control deck,
bill's chair.
Deck, you mean?
I think that's
everything, sir.
It will land 16 minutes
after firing.
Give or take a millionth
of a second.
Excellent timing, whitsun.
Mr. Taplin's claim expired
half an hour ago.
No legal problems.
Are you there?
Yes.
On your right,
two rows of switches.
Bottom row.
Has that guy ever spoken
a complete sentence?
- All right?
- What now?
On your left,
the big front lever.
Pull it all the way back.
But before you do that--
now.
Oh, no smoking
in your pressure suit.
First rule in the book.
Hothead.
I bet he won't
try that again.
Cut the throttle.
The engineer
must have got free.
[Joel as peter lorre]
Yes...
--You think the girl
is flying that thing.
In the maintenance locker,
there is a buzzsaw.
Mr. Kent, can your engineer
land that thing on his own?
Well, he's not good
at parallel parking,
but if it's a diagonal spot,
he can do it.
I don't think so.
Then he needs you
as much as we need the ship.
And vice-versa.
Mr. Kaminski,
if you hear me,
- are you ready to--
- he could've just grabbed that.
Go get him, harry.
That's right, harry,
come and get me.
He's got a gun, mr. Hubbard.
I know that.
It's your gun.
Now start earning your pay
for once.
Uh, I can't spend it
if I got a hole through me.
Be reasonable, mr. Kemp.
We just wanna get back
to the moon same as you do.
So let's have
no more trouble, please.
Watch your head, harry.
How can a person
watch their own head?
Huh?
Ugh...
You didn't hit my head...
Music to shoot thugs by.
Now, let's be reasonable,
mr. Kemp.
Come here.
Light bulbs.
They're surfing.
I can fly! I can fly!
I'm the luckiest boy
in the world!
Well, stop it!
Klink, you idiot!
- The buildup of power--
- I won! I won!
I'm the best! I'm the best!
Works every time.
High five? No,
just a hand is fine, thanks.
Well, they'll be on the moon
before we are.
Seal her up.
We'll follow as far as we can.
And take lots of pictures.
So long, suckers.
Pressure normal. No leaks.
A few lentils, though.
Good one.
Soup lovers will get it.
United nations space--
she missed his forehead.
That's pretty tough to do.
--99b, no sex
is permitted in space.
It's probably because
of the fiberglass suits.
--Most of them.
Nobody else has read it, either.
Wow, apparently I'm dead.
They'll reach the moon
in exactly one minute.
- On target?
- On target.
And whoever takes over
from hubbard
gets 6,000 tons of sapphire.
That makes you
a very attractive woman.
I'm already attractive.
--Was murdered,
and that he'd found nickel.
- Yeah, go on.
- --Allowed,
profit by murder.
- Hmm.
- Five seconds.
Four.
Three.
Yeah! Yee-ha!
- You're fired, sparky.
- Yahoo!
- Whoo!
- Whoo-hoo-hoo!
♪ Moon zero two ♪
--Made his mark
on the moon, all right.
Funny.
Course for moon city.
Oh, by the way,
what's your room
at the hotel like?
Why don't you find out?
I don't get it,
what do you mean?
All right!
She want him to paint
or something?
Yeah.
They also have
a paint contracting outfit.
I hope this turns back
into a cartoon,
kind of to seal
the whole thing up.
- Yeah.
- Bookend it.
- What?
- Kind of bookend it.
Yeah. Yeah.
What is that one song?
Oh, the wiener man song?
Yeah, how does that go?
- Oh, um--
- oh, we have to get
out of here.
♪ I wanna be
your wiener man ♪
♪ I will be
your wiener fan ♪
- Yeah.
- ♪ wieners... ♪
All right, it's the end
of the movie.
Hey, gypsy, how you doing?
- Oh, fine.
- Good, okay,
- it's good to have you back.
- I love you, joel.
Thank you, gypsy.
You're good. Okay.
Now, you know
what we're gonna do next
is do movie review game.
And that means,
tell me a good thing
and a bad thing
about the movie.
And you get a ram chip.
- [Bots cheer]
- Right, a ram chip.
Okay, tom servo.
You go first.
Well, this movie
made my gorge rise.
Okay, and a bad thing?
Okay, seriously.
I thought that the movie
provided an opportunity for us
to examine
the various inaccuracies
often portrayed
in ersatz space movies,
such as this one.
I see, you're really
bucking for that ram chip,
- aren't you, pal?
- Ram chip, ram chip.
- Yeah.
Well, uh, I like it.
You're a good self-starter,
and I like
the cut of your jib.
Here's your ram chip, pally.
All right. All right, crow.
How you doing?
- Ah, fine.
- Do you wanna tell me
a good thing and a bad thing
about the movie?
Uh, it was groovy.
And I mean that
in a good way.
Okay, and the bad thing?
It was groovy.
Right, and you mean that
in a bad way, right?
- Yeah, exactly.
- Okay, all right.
Exactly, okay. Ready?
- Are you ready, girl?
- Yeah.
Okay, tell me a good thing
and a bad thing about the movie.
Richard basehart?
- [Bots moan]
- Richard basehart?
Okay, well,
you get a ram chip.
- What? That's wrong.
- Yeah, okay, good.
All right, okay, well.
We got another letter
to read.
And thanks for everybody
who's written in so far.
You really help us
keep going up here in space.
Cambot, could we have that
up on the screen?
This one comes from
a guy named ryan wiesbrock
from illinois.
Dear joel, tom sirbol--
- huh?
- And crow. Tom sirbol.
I'm 14 years old.
I love your show.
I start laughing so hard
when you make comments
during the movie.
Tears come to my eyes.
Tom sirbol is the best,
- because his voice is so deep--
- thank you.
When he makes a joke,
it sounds funny.
Like when he said,
"oh, I hate to shoot
a butt like that."
Oh, I hate to shoot
a butt like that.
- Right, anyway,
he later asks--
- magical.
About being sirbol,
and it's tom servo.
But it's an honest mistake.
Anyway, there's
a picture here, too.
Show that, cambot.
He's really
a good artist, actually.
So anyway, that ends the
experiment for today.
What do you think, sirs?
What about the address?
I got it. I got it, okay.
Send it to the mystery science
theater 3000 fan club.
P.o. Box 5325.
Hopkins, minnesota.
55343.
Send 'em quick.
Well, not bad. Not bad.
Hey, how's my hair now?
Go like this.
You look like big boy.
File that.
Until next time,
flabby-cakes.
♪♪ [Theme]